bripre the fourth episode
The dictator
This is a nonfictional work. Any resemblance to actual organizations or persons, living or dead, is purely natural.
Chapter: The beginning of affairs.
We #lojban IRC people are experts in Lojban.
Agree, but the official grammar is not useful.
The official grammar is not important.
The Lojban community is governed by us #lojban IRC people.
Agree, we experts are free to modify the grammar.
Agree. Let's modify Lojban of us, by us, for us!
(hand clap)
I make the name words be tanru units (unit of a sequence to be a predicate)!
I make the connectives be in Selpahi's system!
Add new function words and new parts of speech!
Nice, but don't add the words created by Curtis Franks, bah!
Really, nobody use them.
Roger!
The part of speech ZOhOI is done!
Also the part of speech MEhOI is done!
Oh no, new grammar! Our official grammar is great for me.
Agree, no need of modification.
I've exerted to acquire the official grammar. I don't want to learn the new grammar.
The grammar of #lojban IRC is indeed the grammar of modern dialects of Lojban.
I should teach that.
Completed.
Oh, no!
Chapter: Citation of Gleki and #lojban IRC people begins from here.
“The La Gleki's Crash Course (CC)”.
It teaches La Bangu to beginners.
Conflicts with CLL Lojban that break past usage: Here are the differences of modern dialects of Lojban from the language described in CLL. These conflict with what was described in CLL.
This syntactic parser is to be used for La Bangu.
Oh, no, Gleki invaded the official website!
Oh, Gleki completely lacks the procedure of the Language Planning Committe.
Moreover, that parser lacks any information about its creator and is put on the official website.
It should deceive Lojban speakers into believing that that parser is approved by the official body.
I'm sad.
Oh, what happened?
See the part of speech ZOhOI!
You see that implies that Polynesians must be out of Lojban country.
It's first time I tell you: my grand mother is a Polynesian.
I explain.
The parts of speech ZOhOI and MEhOI are labels to a non-Lojban word.
It is said that a non-Lojban word is separated from the nearby words by a pause or a glottal stop.
However, Polynesian languages include words that include glottal stops.
There are therefore some Polynesian words that the parts of speech ZOhOI and MEhOI cannot be labels to.
For example, "zohoi `ul`uli" ("`" is a sign for a glottal stop in Hawaiian language, which is transcripted into a period "." in ASCII notation of Lojban language.)
Therefore, the parts of speech ZOhOI and MEhOI conflict with the concept of neutrality described in the Section 1.1 of the Complete Lojban Language (book).
What a pity. Don't be agonized!
I believe that #lojban IRC people don't intend to hurt you.
Hopelessly, it seems that #lojban IRC people lack the concept of neutrality,
but other than the parts of speech ZOhOI and MEhOI are not very bad to Lojban speakers.
Euh, I don't know.
By the way, the #lojban IRC grammar does not inherit all the beautiful things from Zasni Gerna (Temporal Grammar) of Xorxes,
why?
Probably, the beauty is not important for #lojban IRC people.
I observe, it inherited only something useful to #lojban IRC people.
I think the official grammar is not very favorable in property of structure.
However, I don't want to obey the #lojban IRC grammar, which is ugly to me.
I want to obey another grammar beautiful to me.
Euh, I begin to intend to create a grammar, which I obey.
I will create a syntactic parser that I use.
Nice diversity!
When the function word "jo'au" is in the grammar, there is no reason why there should be only one Lojban grammar.
Yes, using the function word "jo'au", listeners know which version of Lojban the text obeys.
I intend to create and create my grammar, which I obey. I intend to create and create my grammar, which is beautiful to me.
Happily, I try to create my grammar.
Euh, I name my syntactic parser "Zantufa (Favorable Parser)".
Section: I will make the numerals and non-numeral letters separated from each other by the structural property.
"bi ny bajra (There are eight 'n's that run.)"
Completed.
I explain.
For example, "8" is a numeral and "n" is a non-numeral letter.
According to the official grammar, "8n" signifies a number.
for example, "bi ny bajra (There are 8*10+n runners,...)"
and, for making "8" and "n" separated from each other, it is necessary to say "boi", for example,
"bi boi ny bajra (There are 8 n-s that run.)"
Section: I will also make the function word "pi'e" belong to the part of speech VUhU
"li pa bi pi'e re vo (18:24)"
Completed.
I explain.
According to the official grammar, "pa bi pi'e re vo (18:24)"
signifies a number
and depends on only the meaning of "pi'e" for the numeral string being cut by "pi'e".
She also moved "pi'e" to VUhU.
Somewhat worse.
Mayhaps so.
Section: I will modify a little the structure of the part of speech SI,
and also make the function words "ze'ei" and "zei" belong to the part of speech SI.
"li zo'e ze'ei pa (a certain number)"
"mi zei tcita ("me"-label)"
Completed.
I explain.
According to the official grammar, the function word "si" removes syntactic structure of one preceeding word
for example, "oi si coi (Oh dear, oops, Hello!)",
and the function word "zei" makes the two words a tanru unit (unit of a sequence to be a predicate),
for example, "vanci zei coi (Is evening greeting.)"
According to Zantufa, the function word "si" is unchanged,
and the function words "zei" or "ze'ei" connects the meaning of one preceeding word and the syntactic structure of one following word,
for example, "vanci zei coi (Good evening!)"
Aha, Zantufa made the function words "zei" and "ze'ei" belong to the part of speech SI.
Yes, great.
Section: I see the part of speech SA penetrates various structures like a net.
It is very ugly.
Agree, but there is no way for the part of speech SA being simple in structure.
Though even that ugly structure is not satisfactory for what users want.
I remember Xorxes also said that or something similar.
I think, when the part of speech LOhAI is in the grammar,
the part of speech SA is not necessary.
"do pa sanji tu lo'ai pa sa'ai ba le'ai (you, a knower, that, s/pa/ba/ )"
It parses like this,
and then a semantic parser will analyse it like "do ba sanji tu (you will be aware of that.)"
Agree, the part of speech SA is unaware that the function word "pa" is replaced by the function word "ba" like that.
For example, "do pa sanji tu sa ba sanji tu (you, a knower, that -sorry, will be aware of that.)"
Aha!
I will make my grammar clean of the part of speech SA.
I believe the part of speech SA shows ugliness.
I believe the part of speech bothers my grammar.
I say "good-bye!" to the part of speech SA.
I lack the part of speech SA, as I desire.
Joy!
Completed, it became much simple and beautiful.
Section: I will modify the structure of connectives.
"joi gi ti gi ta gi tu (this, that and that over there)
I explain.
According to the official grammar, forethought connectives span over only two items,
for example, "joi gi ti gi ta (this and that)".
"Walk, swim or fly, and sing and dance."
I explain.
According to the official grammar, the function word "gi'i" belongs to the part of speech GIhA, and signifies interrogative,
for example, "do cadzu gi'i se relxilma'e (do you walk or ride a bike?)"
According to Zantufa, the function word "gi'i" is replaced by a string of function words "ji cu",
for example, "do cadzu ji cu se relxilma'e (do you walk or ride a bike?)"
and the function word "gi'i" belongs to the part of speech GIhI" and is a terminator of forethought connectives.
"gi pu bo ba jersi ta gi surla (before future chasing, I take a rest.)"
I explain.
According to the official grammar, the function word "pu" of a forethought connective is put only before the function word "gi",
for example, "pu gi ba jersi ta gi surla".
According to Zantufa, the function word "pu" is put before or after the function word gi.
Completed.
My forethought connectives are useful for various syntactic structures.
My forethought connectives has the power to span over any plural number of items.
There is no reason why the forethought connectives must always span over two items.
Here, there, over there, over there, there and here I go.
This, that, that over there, that over there, that and this are chosen.
There is no reason why the forethought connectives must always span over two items.
This, that, that over there, that over there, that and then this I meet.
This, that, that over there, that over there, that and then this salutes.
Oh dear
Much tinkered.
She repurposed "gi'i"; heh.
huh, she made n-ary "gi"?
Yep
I thought that had really bad ambiguity problems.
I think she fixed it by repurposing "gi'i". Hence the GIhI.
"ta broda je cu brode (that does_1 and does_2.)"
Hm Selpa'i-"jecu" works,
but Selpa'i-"gu je" doesn't work.
oh, zantufa doesn't have "ga je" either. strange.
It is replaced by "gi je", strangely.
As for the following string, non-Zantufa also has to include the similar thing.
"gi ba bo broda gi brode (after doing_1, doing_2)"
Clearly, it has the same meaning as "ba gi",
but if permitting something like this:
"ba gi ba bo broda gi brode (in future, after doing_1, doing_2)"
"ba gi ba bo broda gi brode gi'i je mo (in future, after doing_1, doing_2, and doing what?)"
I should commit pillage for many things of Zantufa.
Euh, oh, it produces "gu'ek (connective for tanru (the sequence of units for a predicate))".
"ge broda gi brode zo'e gi'i (does_1, and does_2 something)"
Broken?
Ah, I made a mistake.
"ge broda gi brode zo'e gi'i (does_1, and does_2 something)"
Completed reparing.
Thanks to the #lojban IRC user who found the bug.
Section: the grammar is concordant with study of logic.
According to the philosophy of Quine, a formula in the structure constructed by the part of speech NU is referencially opaque.
I think therefore a proposition signified by a formula in NU-structure...
and a proposition signified by a formula out of NU structure...
do not always have a common universe of discourse.
Motivated by that, I gave a full logical power to the universe of discourse of NU-structure.
In other words, NU-structure contains a complete formula, that is called a statement in Lojban grammar.
"nu mo .i bo mo (event of doing what, doing what)"
Ah!! I think it is not at all correct.
Intended, though.
The function word "i" is text's main concept.
The function word "i" moves the readers to th 0-th layer,
but according to Zantufa, it ceases moving.
Similar to "gek (the forethought connectives)" in property of incompatibility.
So la zantufa implemented JE cu and repurposed "gi'i",
but did not implement GA JE and GU JE
Wait maybe zantufa took a different approach...
"je gi broda gi brode (doing_1 and doing_2)"
"gi je broda gi brode (doing_1 and doing_2)"
Two versions are approved.
Ah. How does it distinguish between tanru (sequence of units for a predicate) and bridi (predicate relationship; the speaker confuses it with a formula) forethought though?
"gi je cu broda gi cu brode"
I don't know. I tried to make a parser parse in the form of non-tanru forethought and to fail.
Sorry, I meant "tried to make that, and failed."
Oh. "gi je broda gi brode zo'e gi'i je cu mo (does_1 and does_2 something, and does what?)"
Bah, Zantufa uses a secret connective system.
I remember there may be the explanation.
learning by brute force, aha!
Oh no, I made again a mistake.
"gi je broda gi brode zo'e gi'i je cu mo (does_1 and does_2 something, and does what?)"
Completed reparing.
"lo nu broda i bo brode (the event of doing_1, doing_2)"
Magic!
I don't like it.
It conflicts with Gleki's "i bo", though.
What is Gleki's "i bo"?
Gleki says that it is a way of adding a structure of the part of speech UI after completing a sentence.
I observe, it is taught in the Crash Course,
for example, "do pu sidju mi i bo ui (you helped me; happy.)"
Ah, I see.
I observe, that structure is conjunction of a sentence and a vacancy by "i bo".
Generally, the meaning of ui spans over the function word "bo" or the vacancy, not over the preceding text.
Agree. What is taught by Gleki is not concordant with the standard scope system of free modifier of Lojban.
Gleki may want that the meaning taught above is a special property of "i bo ui" among free modifiers.
Why Gleki does not use the function word "vau" in order to add a UI-structure?
Maybe the reason is that "vau" terminates an atomic formula, not a complete formula,
for example, "mi jinvi lo du'u ta mulno vau ui (I think that is completed with happiness.)"
is different from "mi jinvi lo du'u ta mulno vau vau ui (I think that is completed, happy.)"
I see. I will try later another way of scope of ui following after a complete formula.
Oh, deplorable!
now she's gone too far
I should create Maltufa (Deplorable Parser) :p
Everything belongs to UI.
lo'u zei gentufa (Out-of-Structure Parser).
Aha.
"lo nu broda .ije brode"
if "i" doesn't start a new sentence... oi oi oi
Hm yeah I see a problem
it basically eliminates elidible terminators
I don't really use "i bo",
but .ije might be problematic
"lo nu broda .i brode (the event of doing_1. doing_2.)"
so it breaks compositionality as well
NU/NOI is extremely common
and I fear a large amount of text would be broken by changing the semantics of "i" after abstractions.
Changing the semantics of "i" after abstractions would be disastrous, which is why you'd need to explicitly use "tu'e".
For example, "i mi djica lo nu tu'e do klama lo mi zdani i ba bo mi'o samkei kansi'u tu'u (I want that you come to my house and then we play games together.)"
What a pity! TUhE-structure is not what is called a sentence in Lojban grammar, which is an atomic formula.
Therefore, it is not contained in NU-structure of the official grammar or #lojban IRC grammar.
As for Zantufa, there is no problem.
"i mi djica lo nu tu'e do klama lo mi zdani i ba bo mi'o samkei kansi'u tu'u (I want that you come to my house and then we play games together.)"
Like this, "tu'e" is essentially acting as LU,
but the result of which is not a sumti (argument of predicate), but a bridi (predicate relationship; the speaker confuses it with a formula).
That is false. Precisely, it is not an atomic formula but a complete formula.
Well, zantufa currently goes further than that.
Ah, I had missed that. Sorry.
Then I suppose I'm not a big fan of zantufa, aha!
What a pitty! The #lojban IRC people seem to be unable to distinguish a complete formula from an atomic formula.
But maybe being unable to do it is not characteristic of #lojban IRC people only.
But #lojban IRC people generally rebel too much against logic.
Calm down.
Anyone is free to prefer anti-logical dialects of Lojban.
You also, you have not yet explain your dialect being concordant with study of Logic.
I define a complete formula as a formula that is completed by the speaker.
To complete saying a formula is
to make a mapping from a formula to a proposition that has a certain truth-value in the universe of discourse.
For example, to complete a formula "cy morsi ijonai cy xrukla (C is dead XOR C comes back.)"
is to make a mapping from the whole formula to a complex proposition that has the truth value 1 in the universe of discourse.
In that context, the speaker does not assert any truth value of those two atomic formulas connected by the connectives.
That is to say, the speaker assert neither whether C is dead, nor whether C comes back.
Therefore, from a point of view of study of logic, the function word "i" followed by a connective does not terminate a complete formula.
#lojban IRC people lack the concept of study of logic like that.
From a point of view of truth-value, the function word "i" with a connective is different from "i" alone in meaning.
As I said at 21m15s of this movie,
I think that the inside of NU-structure and the outside of it do not always have a common universe of discourse.
Therefore, it seems to me insane to prevent use of afterthought connectives for signifying a truth in the universe of discourse of NU-structure.
Well, it is not very rational from a point of view of study of logic, setting aside whether it is insane.
It's also ugly that NU structure is not recursive at the part of afterthought connectives of a string that signifies a truth.
"broda i ja brode (doing_1 or doing_2)"
"nu broda i ja brode (event of doing_1 or doing_2)"
"nu nu broda ija brode kei ija nu broda ija brode (event of event of doing_1 or doing_2 or event of doing_1 or doing_2)"
Feeling of solidarity. However, I believe that the concepts of logic or beauty are not important for #lojban IRC people.
They are different from us in what is important.
Don't be angry about that.
Roger, sorry.
I kinda like the "gi'i" thing though.
Even though it does break some old constructs that rely on it being binary.
Agree.
What is this "gi'i"?
terminator for n-ary "gi"
Joy, some features of Zantufa are not much deplorable to even #lojban IRC people.
Section: the part of speech KE of the official grammar is not neat in property of structure.
Motivated by that, I made the KE-structure of Zantufa neat.
OK.
I explain.
According to the official grammar,
"broda gi'e ke brode gi'a brodi ke'e (does_1 and [does_2 or does_3].)"
is grammatical,
but "ke broda gi'e brode ke'e gi'a brodi ([does_1 and does_2] or does_3.)"
is ungrammatical.
Zantufa grammar is a result of removing that bug.
"ke broda gi'e brode ke'e gi'a brodi ([does_1 and does_2] or does_3.)"
"ke po'o lo broda cu brode (only the doing_1 does_2.)"
ah I see
This is an extension of ,
first developed to do stuff like this
so how can we fix camxes-exp (parser for #lojban IRC users) to parse this :)
because zantufa has some other problematic features that disqualify it for general use
Yeah I know T.T
note: gleki's new favorite construction "i bo UI" breaks under zantufa's deplorable change to "i"
Aha, #lojban IRC people seem to want to get something from Zantufa grammar.
Agree, they get only useful things, not the main concept.
Just like they ignored the simple and beautiful things of Zasni Gerna (Temporal Grammar) of Xorxes.
Really, #lojban IRC people lack philosophy.
Because of that, their grammar is ugly.
But the ugly-to-you is favorable to #lojban IRC people.
As I said before, it's only that you and they are different from each other in what is favorable.
Section: I don't need the part of speech SE,
because I permit the part of speech FA to have power to span over sumti (argument of predicate) XOR tanru unit (unit of a sequence to be a predicate).
I will make the part of speech SE replaced by the part of speech FA
I expect the grammar will be much simple.
for example, "fe ta tavla (talks to that.)"
has the same meaning as "ta fe tavla (talks to that.)"
and also "fa joi fe mi'o tavla (we talk to each other.)"
has the same meaning as "mi'o fa joi fe tavla (we talk to each other.)"
Simply speaking, they mean that we discuss.
Good-bye, the part of speech SE! Tee-hee!
The part of speech FA was a tag on sumti (argument of predicate).
The part of speech FA of me is a tag on tanru unit (unit of a sequence to be a predicate).
The part of speech FA of me will be a tag on tags XOR connectives.
Good-bye, the part of speech SE! Tee-hee!
Hey, Mankant.
Attention, Mankant.
That is not concordant with the past texts in the property of structure of tag of tags or connectives.
For example, "fe va'u (official: something_1, benefitting from something_2 / zantufa: for the benefit of something_1)"
and "fe gu ra gi ri (official: that, no matter whether this / zantufa: no matter whether that, this)"
Agree, but the function words "ku" and "ke" help the tag of tags and the tag of connectives, respectively.
Look, "fe ku va'u (something_1, benefitting from something_2)".
Also, "fe ke gu ra gi ri (that, no matter whether this)".
Agree, I only made you aware of much difference,
because you have been try to make it enough concordant with texts according to the official grammar.
You may decide as you like, though.
OK.
Euh, yes,
the part of speech FA as a tag of tags or connectives implies being different from the official grammar in logical structure at the part of terms.
Euh, for now, I cannot decide.
I permit for now that the part of speech SE is not yet replaced by the part of speech FA, only in the properties of tag of tags or tag of connectives.
"se va'u i fe va'u (for the benefit of something_1; something_1, benefitting from something_2)"
"se gu ra gi ri i fe gu ra gi ri (no matter whether that, this; that, no matter whether this)"
Though, in the far future, I want to make the parts of speech SE and FA be completely mixed in one.
It would be the favorable parser extreme, aha!
Aha!
And lol Zantufa... she repurposed FA for "to'ai/vo'ai/xo'ai"
wat
Yes
What would the rafsi (combining form for the word) be even :p
Ah, lol. rafsi: faq feq fiq foq fuq
lol
nah I don't like that
it seems useful at first
but it's way inconsistent. conflicts with tag unification.
Section: the structure of the part of speech SEI is strange.
It is different from the structure of the part of speech LE in the property of how many terms it includes.
For example, "sei ca ku ta tu ti sfubu (-now, that dives to over there from here-)"
and "le ti pa sfubu (one diver of this)"
Moreover, it is different from the structure of the part of speech NU in the property of whether it includes an atomic formula.
For example, "sei ca ku ta sfubu tu ti (—now, that dives— that over there, this)"
and "nu ca ku ta sfubu tu ti (event of 'now that dives to over there from here')"
On the one hand, COI-structure is similar to LE-structure,
and TO-structure is similar to LU-structure.
On the other hand, SEI-structure is not harmonious with the other structure in the grammar.
Therefore, it is good to make SEI-structure harmonious with NU-structure.
And then, new SOI of Selpa'i should belong to the part of speech SEI of Zantufa.
"mi sei la'a do na sanji ke'a cu dasni lo cnino se panci (I —maybe you are not aware of it— wear new perfume.)"
Completed.
No, I am aware of it, aha!
Aha!
This would be absolutely devastating.
is very similar to LE
and that's the simplicity of the grammar.
I don't see any need in changing it,
what is more the current grammar of SEI is more advantageous to me.
Gleki seems not to understand that the part of speech SEI is between the parts of speech LE and LU in the property of form.
If you need a function word that has the meaning of sei and the form similar to LE, add a new function word to the part of speech COI.
I'm afraid Zantufa things will soon really cease to be Lojban language, seriously or not.
Agree.
They seem not to be afraid that their own dialects cease to be Lojban language,
why?
Then I believe that they think that their own dialects are still Lojban language.
How egocentric they are!
Well, in any case, it is not rational that they are afraid of a dialect that is not spoken by themselves.
Section: I will add the part of speech IAU so that the part of speech UI following a text should span over a complete formula.
Simply speaking, "i bo" of Gleki is replaced by it, isn't it?
Yes.
That one is thirsty, and this one has property of offering water, happy!
Completed.
You see, "i bo" of Gleki is replaced by the function word "iau".
Yes.
Moreover, it is concordant with study of logic that the function word "iau" terminates only a complete formula.
Nice.
"ke ti ta ke'e ja tu ([this, that] or that over there)"
Strange.
"fa ke ti ta ([this, that])"
Zantufa became out-of-structure parser, non-seriously.
Not at all.
"ti ge ta mo gi tu mo (this does what that, and this does what that over there?)"
!
freakin' jbofi'e (a parser of official YACC grammar) can parse that
shame, zantufa, shame :)
lol
Oh, no, I made again a mistake.
Oh, #lojban IRC people are too much impolite.
Mankant, don't be agonized!
I'm not agonized by those who lack philosophy.
"ti ge ta mo gi tu mo (this does what that, and this does what that over there?)"
Completed reparing.
In Zantufa, the function word "ce'e" belongs to the part of speech BO,
but what is the profit?
What can be the meaning of something like "mi je ce'e do"?
From a point of view of Zantufa, I want to remove the function word "ce'e",
but I permit "ce'e" be in the grammar in order to parse a text in the official grammar that includes "ce'e".
There is no meaning of "mi je ce'e do".
"ro mo ge mo gi mo (every how doing what and doing what)"
I think it is not correctly parsed.
The official asserts it:
"ro mo ge mo gi mo (every what does what and does what?)"
From a point of view of Zantufa, the function words belonging to the part of speech GUhA is not necessary, and they became function words of the part of speech GA.
"ro mo cu ge mo gi mo (every what does what and does what?)"
or "ro mo ge cu mo gi mo (every what does what and does what?)"
has the structure similar to that of the official grammar, though not the same.
I explain.
On the one hand, according to the official grammar, the part of speech GUhA spans over tanru (sequence of units for a predicate), and the part of speech GA does not,
for example, "ge gu'a crino gi xunre gi sinxa (it is green or red, and is signal.)"
By the way, The parts of speech GA and GUhA of the official grammar span over only two items, therefore "ge" spans over "sinxa", "gu'a" does not.
On the other hand, according to Zantufa, the part of speech GA spans over tanru (sequence of units for a predicate), too,
for example, "ge ga crino gi pelxu gi xunre gi cu sinxa (it is green, yellow or red, and is signal.)"
That is, PEG is more powerful than YACC in describing grammar,
so the part of speech GUhA of YACC grammar is not necessary any more for the grammar described in PEG, is it?
Yes.
So, Zantufa language is enough different from Lojban language.
Chapter: Result of the affairs
Oh, Gleki also says that your language is not Lojban language.
Oh, he also pushes my language out of the set of Lojban languages.
Howerver, I remember that Gleki taught beginners that #lojban IRC dialects are modern Lojban.
Feeling of solidarity.
Anyone may opine that what is Lojban language, and what is not,
but the following matter is really problem:
Gleki uses the official website account and the official-pretending accounts in order to publish his own opinion.
That fact misleads anyone interested in Lojban into believing that Gleki's opinion is the official opinion.
I put up with #lojban IRC people assert that #lojban IRC dialects are Lojban and Zantufa is not Lojban.
Continue your terms of abuse on Zantufa!
However, it is intolerable that Gleki uses the official or official-pretending accounts.
It results in Lojban language being uniformly #lojban IRC dialects.
It results in my loosing my place in Lojban community.
Really violent and dictator, Gleki is.
I will never forgive him.
Sung in Zantufa dialect.
Do you feel the color fissure?
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
"Deplorable, deplorable!"
said who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure?
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
"You cease to be Lojbanic."
said who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure? (color-fissure)
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
"I am indeed the norm."
said who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure?
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
I said "This is my language."
to who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure?
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
I said "You expelled me."
to who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure? (color-fissure)
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
I said "Farewell to you."
to who was once a friend of mine.
Do you feel the color fissure?
Much rational according to every preferable syntactic form.
If there is a bridge across the color fissure,
then you'll be again a friend of mine.
—There is no bridge.
End
not yet.
You will make this movie show finished in the following way.
Below is spoken in Zantufa dialect version 1.17.
Every line is spoken by Guskant,
but I want the lines of other than Bripre or Mankant to be spoken by others.
Chose one of the roles, record the lines in your voice, and send the sound recording to Bripre or Guskant.
I will make the proper lines of the movie be replaced by your voice.
I want, but don't expect, that the lines of #lojban IRC people or Gleki will be spoken by the original writer of the lines.
When all lines of other than Bripre or Mankant are spoken by other than Guskant, the movie show is finished.
End of the way of finishing the movie show.
Thank you helpers in advance.